# Serena Badesha

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

	07468439279
$\bowtie$	sbadesha@gmail.com
₽	https://www.linkedin.com/in/seren a-badesha-3b4450103/
9	Liverpool

#### **PROFILE**

Software developer with 2 years' experience in C and iOS development. Personal passion is making the community better through technology and making people's lives easier with the use of technologies that could benefit both people and the environment around us. Currently seeking an exciting opportunity to apply the knowledge and skills acquired at university and expand on them for my personal and professional development.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **University of York**

MEng Electronic Engineering with Music Technology Systems

Grade: 2.1(1st in master's year)

2015-2021 Projects

- Additive and wavetable synthesizers created in pure data.
- Graphical projectile-based game written in C for Ubuntu.
- Wavetable synthesizers and accelerometer project using C and Embedded systems.
- Sonified a weather station using C and Embedded systems.
- Graphical flocking simulation written in Java.
- Path finding project written in C.
- iOS application 'Live synth' written in Swift using XCode.
- Vocal tremor detector written in MATLAB.
- Simple operating system written in C and Assembly for an ARM processor.
- Physical modeling library of different instruments and rooms.
- Final year project was to Resurrect an Auditory model. A new application was developed in MATLAB from Visual basic along with a detailed 85-Page academic report.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Research and Development Engineer Intern**

MQA Ltd.

2019-2021

- Modernised an auditory model from Visual Basic 4.0 to MATLAB.
- Designed and develop example iOS apps in Objective-C/C++ for client use.
- Studied and reproduced audio algorithms from AES papers in Octave.
- Liaised with partner companies on example software for the Raspberry Pi 4(C++).
- Influenced and contributed to the maintenance and improvement of libraries in C++ including:
  - o Set up VM infrastructure for Valgrind use.
  - Latex based autogenerated documentation.
- Test and produced feedback for Android apps.
- Wrote and maintained Jenkins jobs.
- Mentored succeeding interns.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Swift 5
- Objective-C
- C/C++
- Godot
- Linux-Ubuntu, Raspbian, Debian
- MATLAB
- Google Test
- Fork/Bitbucket
- Github/GitLab
- Jenkins

# **PROJECTS**

Github -

https://github.com/SerenaMB1

- Ray tracer. Currently building a ray tracer from scratch in C++ and integrating google test.
- Shade app. Journaling app built for iPhone using Swift 5 in XCode.
- 2-Player Brick Breaker. web browser game written in Godot.

# OTHER EDUCATION

# Richmond-Upon-Thames College

BTEC Extended diploma in Music Technology - Distinction\* Distinction\* Distinction\* A-level in Computing – B

#### **Coombe Girls School**

11.5 GCSEs, grade A\*- B including Maths and English

# Serena Badesha

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

	07468439279
$\bowtie$	sbadesha@gmail.com
₽	https://www.linkedin.com/in/serena-badesha-3b4450103/
0	Liverpool

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Student Ambassador**

University of York 2019-2021

 Communicate positively with staff, students and prospective students about university life providing a deep in sight using a broad knowledge of the university.

## **Studio Technician**

Kingston Music Service 2011-2018

- Fix technical problems with recording software.
- Diagnose and troubleshoot problems with physical connections to the computer.
- Use creativity and spatial awareness / scientific knowledge of microphone placement to produce recordings.
- Demonstrate an in-depth knowledge of technology in industry and in the inventory.

#### AWARDS

- Junction Hackathon (Major League Hacking) 2018 Partner Challenge Winning Team.
- Performing Arts Student of the Year Award at Richmond Upon Thames College (1 per cohort).
- Musical Grade 5 Music theory and Drum kit.
- Duke of Edinburgh Bronze and Silver.
- York Award An award that recognizes active participation in university life.